Guide to the Black Panther collection, circa 1967-1973.
Black Panther collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Black Panther collection, circa 1967-1973.
8069
Black Panther Party.
Approximately 1.5 cubic feet (115 items).
Printed materials and publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Publications, posters, handbills, flyers and news clippings covering the activities of the Black Panthers and several of its members. Publications include issues of the periodicals The Black Panther, Black Panther community newsletter, Liberated guardian, Open city, and The Berkeley tribe, and pamphlets by Huey P. Newton and Kim Il Sung. Many of the posters, handbills, and flyers concern Huey P. Newton, Bobby Seale, or Eldridge Cleaver. Other items include a cover proof for If they come in the morning by Angela Y. Davis.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Publications, posters, handbills, flyers and news clippings covering the activities of the Black Panthers and several of its members. Publications include issues of the periodicals The Black Panther, Black Panther community newsletter, Liberated guardian, Open city, and The Berkeley tribe, and pamphlets by Huey P. Newton and Kim Il Sung. Many of the posters, handbills, and flyers concern Huey P. Newton, Bobby Seale, or Eldridge Cleaver. Other items include a cover proof for If they come in the morning by Angela Y. Davis.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Black Panther Party.; Cleaver, Eldridge, 1935-1998.; Cleaver, Eldridge, 1935-1998; Davis, Angela Y. (Angela Yvonne), 1944-; Kim, Il-sŏng, 1912-1994.; Newton, Huey P.; Newton, Huey P.; Newton, Huey P.; Seale, Bobby, 1936-; Seale, Bobby, 1936-; Black Panther Party; Black Panther Party.
Form and Genre Terms:
Posters.; Fliers (printed matter).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Publications
  - Subseries Ia. Black Panther Community News Service
    - No. 4, You Can't Jail a Revolution, 1969-09-01 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Vol. 1, No. 6, Huey Must be Set Free!, 1967-11-23 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Vol. 3, No. 21, Next Victim of Fascist Frameup?, 1969-09-13 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Vol. 4, No. 3, By lifting their hands against these revolutionaries, 1969-12-20 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Year misidentified on cover as 1967
    - Vol. 2, No. 2, Free All Black Political Prisoners, 1968-05-04 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Vol. 2, No. 23, Happy Birthday Huey, 1969-02-17 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Vol. 2, No. 25, Viva Zapata 1883-1919, 1969-03-09 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Vol. 2, No. 28, Chairman Bobby Seale Returns From Scandinavia, 1969-03-31 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Vol. 3, No. 8, Capitalism Plus Racism Breeds Fascism, 1969-06-14 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Vol. 3, No. 9, Reagan’s Fascist Pigs Vamp on Sacramento HQ, 1969-06-21 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Vol. 3, No. 11, Eldridge Cleaver Breaks His Silence, 1969-07-05 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Vol. 3, No. 12, 1969-07-12 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Vol. 3, No. 14, United Against Fascism, 1969-07-26 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Vol. 3, No. 22, Our Fight Is Not in Vietnam, 1969-09-20 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Vol 3, No. 24, Bobby Seale, Chairman, 1969-10-04 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Vol. 3, No. 28, Political Prisoners of USA Fascism, 1969-11-01 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Vol. 4, No. 4, Although my body may be bound and shackled…, 1969-12-27 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Vol. 4, No. 8, The Invincible Thoughts of The Black Panther Party Can Never Be Destroyed By Fire Nor Water, 1970-01-31 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Vol. 4, No. 10, Happy Birthday Huey, 1970-02-17 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Vol. 4, No. 14, Hunter’s Point 1967; Hunter’s Point 1970, 1970-03-07 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Vol. 4, No. 18, He Was The Beginning: Lil Bobby Hutton, 1970-04-06 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Vol. 4, No. 20, “This Is But An Aspect Of The Unfolding Picture Of American Fascism,”, 1970-04-18 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Vol. 4, No. 22, ‘The Black Panther Party is the People’s Party and We Are Primarily Interested in Freeing Man.’, 1970-05-02 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Vol. 4, No. 24, The Heirs of Malcolm Have Picked Up The Gun and Now Stand Millions Strong Facing The Racist Pig Oppressor, 1970-05-19 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Vol. 4, No. 25 and 26, Babylon, 1970-05-31 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Vol. 5, No. 7, Revolutionary Suicide, 1970-08-15 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Vol. 5, No. 8, If The Penalty for the Quest for Freedom is Death—Then by Death We Escape to Freedom, 1970-08-21 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Vol. 5, No. 10, Lonnie McLucas, 1970-09-05 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Vol. 5, No. 17, Rent-A-Pid Kills 14 Year Old Brother In Homemade Playground, 1970-10-24 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Vol. 5, No. 20, On The Battlefield In Cairo, Illinois, 1970-11-14 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Vol. 5, No. 24, New York City…Criminal Slumlords Are Crime Partners With City Government Officials and Courts, 1970-12-26 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Vol. 5, No. 26, The Last Christmas???, 1970-12-14 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Vol. 5, No. 28, In the spirit of revolutionary solidarity, 1971-01-09 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Subseries Ia. Black Panther Intercommunal News Service
    - Vol. 6, No. 5, The San Quentin Branch of The Black Panther Party Opens!, 1971-02-27 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Vol. 6, No. 9, The World is Yours, As Well As Ours, 1971-03-27 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Vol. 6, No. 11, Black Genocide: Sickle Cell Anemia, 1971-04-10 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Vol. 7. No. 12, World War III?, 1971-11-13 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Vol. 7, No. 19, Cease-fire Verdict in L.A., 1972-01-01 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Vol. 7, No. 25, Another Mother For Struggle, 1972-02-12 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Vol. 7, No. 28. Welcome Home, Angela Davis, 1972-03-04 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Vol. 7, No. 29, The Glass Cage Must Come Down!, 1971-08-14 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Vol. 8, No. 5, No Eviction, Free Repairs—If You Were Your Own Landlord, 1972-04-22 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Vol. 8, No. 21, Survival Pending Liberation, 1972-08-12 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Vol. 9, No. 26, Vote April 17th, 1973-04-14 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Center spread only, "24 Hour Vigils for Eldridge Cleaver", 1968-12-07 (Box 1)
  - Subseries Ia. Other publications
    - Right On! Black Community News Service, Vol. 1, No. 1, Deputy Field Marshall Robert Webb Slain by Huey’s Assassins, 1971-04-03 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Right On! Revolutionary Peoples Communication Network. 32 Political Prisoners Murdered in Attica Prison, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
    - Right On! Revolutionary Peoples Communications Network, Vol. 1, No. 3, Special Issue: The Peoples Republic of Congo, 1971-08-03 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - The Black Panther, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Liberated Guardian, 1970-05-01 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Open City, No. 64, 1968-08-09 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Open City, No. 65, 1968-08-16 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Hustler!, 1968-11-14 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - The Berkeley Tribe, center spread, 1970-02-13 (Box 1)
    - "The Panthers of Wrath are Wiser than the Horses of Instruction" clipping from unidentified newspaper, Undated (Box 1)
- Series II. Fliers, Handbills, and Posters
  - Zaterdatg 14 Maart … Eldridge Cleaver komt naar Nederland Toe, Undated; Handbill (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Netherlands
  - Vrÿheidsschool, Rozenstraat 6: Alle macht aan het volk, Undated; Flier (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Who is Huey P. Newton?, Undated; Huey Newton Defense Fund; Packet (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Notes on the Black Panther Party for Self Defense and the Peace and Freedom Movement, Undated; Packet (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Notes on the Black Panther Party for Self Defense and the Peace and Freedom Movement, 1968; Handbill (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Black Panther Party – Why?, 1968; Handbill (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Who is Huey P. Newton?, Undated; Huey Newton Defense Fund; Packet (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Essays from the Minister of Defense, 1968; Newton, Huey P. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Berkeley
  - College of Malcolm X, 1969; Pamphlet (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Santa Cruz, CA
  - Eldridge Cleaver is Running for President.”, 1968; Campus Peace and Freedom; Pamphlet (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Each of you should be prepared to be a match for one hundred, 1970; New World Liberation Front; Sung, Kim Il; Pamphlet (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Alprentice Bunchy Carter Free Clinic, Undated; Flier (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Los Angeles Area
  - Walk Wendell, Undated; Flier (Box 6, Folder 2)
    South Pasadena, CA
  - John Huggins Free Hot Breakfast Program for Children, Undated; Flier (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Los Angeles
  - Occupying Pigs Running Amok, Undated; Flier (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Protests of the film Superfly, 1972; Packet (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Newark, NJ
  - Cover proof for If They Come in the Morning, 1971; Davis, Angela (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Liberation News Service #370 cover, 1971-08-25 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    New York
  - Conference: Nigeria Biafra Relief, 1969-04; Flier (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Friends of the Black Panthers: Bobby Seale rappin’ and Phil Ochs singin’…, Undated">; Flier (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Liberation News Service #370 cover, Undated1970-04-18">1970-04-18 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - What Are the Facts? Who Are the Real Criminals?, Undated; Poster (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Philadelphia
  - Huey P. Newton Ralley, 1970-02; Flier (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - What We Want: October 1966 Black Panther Party Platform, 1966-10; Poster (Box 1)
    New Haven
  - Power to the People, Undated; Poster|pamphlet (Box 1)
  - "Ramparts" Bobby Seale, 1970-01; Poster (Box 1)
  - May Day… Free Huey Day – Mass Rally…, 1969-04; Poster (Box 1)
    San Francisco, CA
  - Free David Hilliard – Black Panther Party – Free All Political Prisoners, 1971; Poster (Box 1)
  - Ramparts mounted cover, 1970-01 (Box 1)
  - Black Panther Party: Central Headquarters. Unused letterhead, Undated (Box 1)
  - Vote For Survival: Bobby Seale for Mayor of Oakland, 1973; Poster (Box 1)
  - Elaine Brown for Councilwoman of Oakland, 1973; Poster (Box 1)
    Oakland
  - Bobby Seale for Mayor of Oakland, 1973; Poster (Box 1)
  - Here and Now for Bobby Seale, Undated; Poster (Box 1)
  - Seize the Time, Undated; Poster (Box 1)
  - Untitled poster designed by Emory Douglas: Mother and Child, Undated; Douglas, Emory; Poster (Box 1)
  - The Black Panther Party: 40th Reunion and Celebration, 2006; Poster (Box 1)
  - Free Huey Newton: Stokely Carmichael, Kathleen Cleaver, Eldridge Cleaver, Bobby Seale., Undated; Poster (Box 1)
  - George Jackson, Field Mashal, Black Panther Party, Undated; Poster (Box 1)
  - 56 vintage newspaper and magazine clippings relating to the Black Panther Party, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - End Racist Attacks on Panthers—Rely on Workers, Not Lawyers!, Undated; Progressive Labor Party; Flier|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Attica…, 1972; United Defense to Free Political Prisoners (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cisco-Kidd Pig Rizzo Oinks Again! Gunman Slain by Police, 1970; Flyer|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The People Must Free the 21!!, 1970; Flyer|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Community Meetings with the Black Panther Party, 1970-1972; Flyer|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Revolutionary Intercommunal Solidarity Day Rally, 1970; Flyer|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Where’s the Conspiracy, Free the Panther 21, 1970; Flyer|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - It’s a Free Country… Isn’t it?, 1969; Flyer|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Black People Boycott, 1965-1969; Flyer|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - People’s No. 1 Enemy, 1970-1974; Flyer|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Free the Panther 21, Free All Political Prisoners, 1970; Handbill|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - You Can Help The Harlem 4, 1972; Charter Group for a Pledge of Conscience; Flyer|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Relocations, 1969-1970; Flyer|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - First You… Now Your Children…, 1965-1970; Flyer|Mimeograph (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Free the N.Y. 21, 1970; Flyer (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Over the Bridge; On to the Jail; People’s Power; Is the Panther’s Bail!, 1969-1972; Flyer (Box 3, Folder 16)
    advertising march in Queens, New York to free the Panther 21, Bobby Seale, and all political prisoners
  - Humanity, Freedom, Peace, 1971; New World Liberation Front|Afro-American Liberation Army (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Black News, Vol. 2, No. 1, 1973-04-01 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Angela Davis Newsletter: Harris Still Fails to Implicate Angela, 1972; Philadelphia Committee To Free Angela Davis; Political newsletter (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Contains article regarding Angela Davis' charges and trial in regards to the Soledad Brothers, as well as a list of happenings (rallies, fundraisers, and other events), and bookstores related to the Black Panther Party in Philadelphia.
  - John Huggins Free Hot Breakfast Program for Children, 1970; Poster|Mimeograph (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sickle Cell Anemia, 1970-1974; Flyer (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Black Panther Party, William Kunstler, and Dave Dellinger are Not Speaking at Bryant Park Today Because…, 1970; Flyer (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Black Panther Intercommunal New Service, 1971-12-26; This special issue of the Black Panther Party newspaper was printed in Vietnamese and features an illustration of a member of the National Liberation Front (Viet Cong) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    No. 5 (Vietnamese)
  - Free David Hilliard, Free All Political Prisoners, 1971; Poster|Screenprint (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Text on poster reads, “Railroaded to prison: June 12, 1971. There were no Black People on the jury in the case of David Hilliard, although 38% of the Oakland Community is Black.”
  - “The Black Panther Party 40th Year Reunion and Celebration”, 2006; Poster (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Contains full color reproduction of illustration by Emory Douglas, Ministry of Culture for the Black Panther Party, and information regarding the Black Panther Party reunion in Oakland, California. Two copies.
  - Here and Now For Bobby Seale, 1970; Poster|Screenprint (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Text reads, “Here and Now For Bobby Seale, We must save Bobby Seale because we must save the Black Panther Party because we must save the revolutionary spirit in America.”
  - On the 13th Anniversary of the Assassination of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., Join Us In A March Against Racist Violence!, 1981; Poster|Screenprint (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Ramparts, 1970; Poster (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - “War Sucks” button, Undated; MU-1744 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - “All Power to The People” and photograph of Huey P. Newton button, Undated; MU-1745 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Button with sepia print photograph of Bobby Hutton, first member of the Black Panther Party, Undated; MU-1746 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Button with black peace sign on white background., Undated; MU-1747 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Button with sepia print photograph of Eldridge Cleaver, Undated; MU-1748 (Box 3, Folder 19)